"He sprang
to his sleigh
"To his team
gave a whistle
"And away they all flew
like the down of a thistle.
"But I heard him exclaim
ere he drove out of sight
'Merry Christmas to all,
and to all a good night!'"
Wow! That was great!
You really wrote that?
Uh-huh.
Say good-bye, elves,
I'm off to Tulsa.
Oh, I can't believe
you're not going to
be here for Christmas.
You're really not coming back?
Yeah.
We have all this paperwork
that needs to be filed
by the end of the year.
If I don't get it done,
I'll be fired.
Just, it's so unfair.
You don't even like your job.
So, who does?
Oh, I like my job.
I love my job.
I can't wait
to go back to work.
I can't get enough dinosaurs.
I'm sorry I won't be here.
It's hard enough
not seeing you
during the week
but for Christmas...
But if this is what you
have to do, I understand.
Thanks.
I'll see you New Year's Day.
You're not going to be
here New Year's Eve?!
Did I not mention that?
No.
And to all a good night!
♪ So no one told you
life was gonna be this way ♪
♪ Your job's a joke,
you're broke ♪
♪ Your love life's D.O.A. ♪
♪ It's like you're always
stuck in second gear ♪
♪ When it hasn't been
your day, your week ♪
♪ Your month,
or even your year ♪
♪ But I'll be there for you ♪
♪ When the rain starts to pour ♪
♪ I'll be there for you ♪
♪ Like I've been there before ♪
♪ 'Cause you're there
for me, too. ♪
All right, everybody
I know that it is
Christmas Eve
and you'd rather be
with your families.
But there is no call
for writing
"Screw You, Mr. Bing"
on the back of my chair.
By the way, you can
all call me Chandler.
Hey.
Hey, where've you been?
Oh, I was checking out
that insurance company's
Christmas party on three.
I mean, it was really beautiful.
They have all these decorations
and this huge tree
and I just thought, "To hell
with them, we have to work."
So I stole their ham.
You hear that?
You may not be
with your families
but at least it's going
to smell like ham in here.
My kid's in a play right now.
You know what, I know
what will cheer you guys up.
Had a little talk with the boys
in New York
told them about all
the hard work you've been doing
and that a little
Christmas bonus may be in order.
"A donation has been
made in your name
to the New York City Ballet."
Well, that's like money
in your pocket.
All right, look,
you want me to say it?
This sucks. Being here sucks.
This work sucks!
Now it feels like Christmas.
I'm sorry.
Hey, at least you guys
get to go home
and be with
your families tonight.
I have to go back
to an empty hotel room
and lay down on
a very questionable bedspread.
And then tomorrow morning
you get to have Christmas
morning in your own houses
which by the way,
none of you have invited me to.
You can come to my house.
( chuckles ):
No, thanks.
That's a nice pep talk.
Oh, thanks.
I'm actually thinking about
becoming a motivational speaker.
So, if you were home right now,
what would you be doing?
Typical Christmas Eve stuff,
you know.
Our holidays
are pretty traditional.
Um, so here's a very
special holiday song
that I wrote for some very
important people to me.
( guitar strums )
♪ Went to the store,
sat on Santa's lap ♪
♪ Asked him to bring my friends
all kinds of crap ♪
♪ Santa, all you need
is to write them a song ♪
♪ They haven't heard it yet,
so don't try to sing along ♪
♪ No, don't sing along ♪
( guitar playing )
♪ Monica, Monica,
have a happy Hanukkah ♪
♪ Saw Santa Claus,
he said hello to Ross ♪
♪ And please tell Joey,
Christmas will be snowy! ♪
♪ And Rachel and Chandler,
how's the... handler? ♪
Happy holidays, everybody.
( applause )
Okay, Pheebs,
you look in the kitchen
I will look in
the back closet, okay?
I can save you
time, ladies.
I'm right here.
Yeah.
Chandler, why don't you
take a walk.
This doesn't concern you.
We are looking for
our Christmas presents
from Monica.
What? That's terrible.
No, no, we do it
every year.
Oh, well, that-that
makes it not terrible.
No. Yeah, we never find them.
She's always bested us,
that wily... minx.
Yeah, don't worry.
We're just going to search here
for an hour
and then we're going to go over
to Joey's and search, okay?
No, not okay.
You can't look
for Monica's presents.
Oh, no, we have to.
No, you don't have to.
And you can't
because I-I live here, too.
Well, then,
you should look with us.
Why?
Chandler,
aren't you worried
about what to get
Monica for Christmas?
No, I have a great idea
for a present for her.
Oh, that's it?
"A great idea." Oh, yeah.
Chandler,
that's not enough.
What if she gets
you a great present
two medium presents, and
a bunch of little presents
and you've just gotten
her one great present?
I mean, that's just going
to make her feel bad.
Why would you do that to
her, Chandler? Why? Why?
If I help,
we could find them faster!
That's right.
Ooh!
Ooh, we have a live one.
Oh! It's a Macy's bag!
Yeah.
Oh!
Ooh, who's it for?
"Dear losers,
do you really think
I'd hide presents
under the couch?"
"P.S. Chandler, I knew
they'd break you."
Rach, these are for you.
Wiper blades.
I don't even have a car.
No, but with
this new car smell,
you'll think you do.
Okay, Pheebs,
your turn.
Oh!
Toilet seat covers!
Is that what you were doing
while I was getting gas?
Uh-huh.
You guys...
JOEY:
Okay, and for Ross
Mr. Sweet Tooth...
You got me a cola drink?
And... a lemon lime!
Well... well, this...
this is too much.
I feel like I should get
you another sweater.
And last,
but not least...
They're ribbed
for your pleasure.
Hey, Ben
what if the
Holiday Armadillo
told you all about
the Festival of Lights?
Cool!
Right.
Come on, Ben.
Years and years ago
there were these people
called the Maccabees!
Ho, ho, ho!
Merry Christmas!
Santa!
Hey!
What are you
doing here, Santa?
Well, I'm here to see
my old buddy Ben.
What are you doing here,
weird... turtle... man?
I'm the Holiday
Armadillo
your part-Jewish
friend.
You sent me here to give
Ben some presents.
Remember?
What?
Ben, why don't you come
open some more presents.
And Santa,
the Armadillo and I
will have a little talk
in the kitchen.
There's a sentence
I'd never thought I'd say.
What are you doing?!
You called everyone and said
you were having trouble
finding a Santa costume.
So I borrowed one
from a guy at work.
Thank you, but-but...
you got to leave.
Why?
Because I'm finally getting him
excited about Hanukkah
and then you're...
you're wrecking it.
But I didn't get
to shake my belly
like a bowl full of jelly.
I'm sorry, Chandler, but this,
this is really important to me.
Fine, I'll, I'll give
the suit back.
Hey...
you think you can
keep it another night?
Santa? Really?
Yeah, is that okay?
Did your Dad ever
dress up like Santa?
No.
Then it's okay!
You know what?
Everybody, go home.
You should be with
your families.
It's bad enough that
we're working New Year's Eve.
Did I not tell anyone
about New Year's Eve?
Oh, all right, look, go.
Go home, okay.
Merry Christmas.
Go.
ALL:
Merry Christmas.
Peace on Earth.
Bye.
Good.
God speed,
good people.
You're not going to go?
Nah. I couldn't
leave you alone.
Ah, thanks.
Besides, I can't leave
until that Christmas party
downstairs clears out.
There are some pissed-off
insurance people
looking for that ham.
Ah.
( telephone rings )
Chandler Bing.
Hi, honey, we're all here.
We just want to wish you
a Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas!
Blah, blah!
Oh, Merry Christmas.
I miss you guys.
So is it horrible?
Is everybody
working really hard?
Ah, well, no.
It's just me and Wendy.
Wendy?
That sounds like a girl's name.
It is.
Did I not tell you about her?
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm
about the time you told me
about New Year's Eve.
Where is everybody else?
I sent them home.
Oh, you are such
a good boss.
Is she pretty?
Uh, uh...
Answer faster,
answer faster.
I don't know.
Answer better,
answer better.
I don't think of her that way,
you know.
She's a... she's a colleague.
What does she do there?
Oh, she's
Regional Vice President.
She's just below me.
She did what?!
Be-low me.
Oh, wait, is Wendy
the runner-up Miss Oklahoma?
What?
Well, sh-she didn't win.
All right, well,
maybe I should let you
and the second prettiest girl
in Oklahoma get back to work.
Well, second prettiest
that year.
I mean, of all the girls
in Oklahoma, she's probably...
Oh, Chandler, stop talking.
Honey, there's really nothing
to worry about.
Okay.
I'm serious.
Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas, you guys.
Blah-blah gla, bla gla.
The wife says hi.
Ah, fun conversation?
Oh, well, she's just got
this weird idea
that just because
you and I are alone
that something's
going to happen.
Uh? Really?
Hmm, would that be
so terrible?
This is probably the wrong
thing to be worrying about
but you're getting ham
on my only tie.
Whoa, whoa,
back off, Missy.
( chuckles )
Missy?
I don't know--
I'm not used to girls
making passes at me.
Wait a minute.
Am I sexy in Oklahoma?
You are to me.
No... no...
No!
Look, I'm...
I'm married.
So? I'm married.
I'm happily married.
Oh. What's that like?
Right. so,
I'm sorry, but...
Seriously?
Happily married?
So that phone call before,
that was happy?
Well, look,
it's not easy
to spend this much
time apart.
She's entitled
to be a little paranoid.
Or in this case,
right on the money.
But look, you know,
she's amazing
and beautiful and smart.
And if she were here
right now
she'd kick your ass.
Look, you're
a really nice person--
ham stealing
and adultery aside--
but what I have
with my wife
is pretty great.
So, nothing's ever going
to happen between us.
Okay, let me
ask you something.
If what you and your
wife have is so great
then why are you spending
Christmas with me?
You were the most beautiful
woman in the room tonight.
Really?
Are you kidding?
You're the most
beautiful woman
in most rooms.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
what's going on?
You and I just made out.
You and I are making out?
Well, not anymore.
But we don't do that.
I know.
I just thought it would be fun.
How drunk are you?
Drunk enough that I know
I want to do this.
Not so drunk that you
should feel guilty
about taking advantage.
That's the perfect amount.
You know what's weird?
What?
This doesn't feel weird.
I know.
You're a really
good kisser.
Well, I have kissed
over four women.
You want to get
under the covers?
Uh-huh.
Okay.
Wow, you
are really fast.
It bodes well for me
that speed impresses you.
We're going to see
each other naked.
Yup.
You want to do it
at the same time?
Count to three?
One...
Two, three.
two, three.
Well, I think it's safe to say
that our friendship
is effectively ruined.
Ah, we weren't
that close anyway.
Yeah.
So, are you really going
to go out with that nurse man?
Well, you and I
are just goofing around.
I thought, why not just goof
around with him?
You know, I don't know
if you've ever looked up
the term "goofing around"
in the dictionary.
Well, I have.
And the technical definition is:
Two friends who care
a lot about each other
and have amazing sex...
and just...
want to spend
more time together.
But if you have
this newfangled dictionary
that gets you mad at me
then we have to, you know,
get you my original dictionary.
I am so bad at this.
I think you're better
than you think you are.
Really?
Okay... So, if...
Know when to stop.
You know, I sense
that I should stop.
So we're okay?
Yeah.
Don't do the dance.
Right.
Okay, come on.
I can't get married
until I get something old,
something new
something borrowed
and something blue.
Okay, okay, okay.
Here's something...
Here's something blue and new.
You're so efficient.
I love you.
Let's go.
No, no, no, wait!
We need something old.
Uh, okay, I have
a condom in my wallet
that I've had
since I was 12.
That'll work.
I don't think so.
Okay, now we just need
something borrowed.
Here, just take this.
That's stealing.
We'll bring it back.
Just put it
under your dress.
Oh...
Okay, one thing at a time.
Listen, um...
I've been thinking.
It's not fair of me to ask you
to spend all of your money
on our wedding.
I mean, you work...
you work really hard for that.
Well...
Well, you work for that.
Look, I've thought
about it, too, and...
I'm sorry.
I think we should spend
all of the money
on the wedding.
You do?
Yeah. I'm putting
my foot down.
( chuckles )
Yeah, look,
when I proposed
I told you that I would do
anything to make you happy.
And if having
the perfect wedding
makes you happy
then... then that's
what we're going to do.
Hmm, you are so sweet.
Oh...
What about... what about
the future and stuff?
Ah, forget about
the future and stuff.
So we only have two kids.
You know, we'll
pick our favorite
and that one will
get to go to college.
You've thought about that?
Yeah.
How many kids
were we going to have?
Ah, four.
A boy, twin girls
and another boy.
What else
did you think about?
Well, stuff like where
we'd live, you know.
Like a small place
outside the city
where our kids could learn
to ride their bikes and stuff.
And, you know,
we could have a cat
that had a bell on its collar,
and we could hear it
every time it ran
through the little kitty door.
'Course, we'd have
an apartment over the garage
where Joey could grow old.
You know what?
I don't want
a big, fancy wedding.
Sure you do.
No.
I want everything
that you just said.
I want a marriage.
You sure?
Mm-hmm.
I love you so much.
I love you.
( gasps )
Aw... I love it!
Really? You're not going
to return it?
Well, not this second.
Hey, look, you guys,
it's snowing!
Hey.
Oh, wow,
it's so beautiful.
Wow, it really is.
Oh...
Wendy's a fat girl name.
Aren't we done with that?
Okay, fine... fine.
Let's talk about snow.
You think
it's snowing in Tulsa
where my husband's having sex
on a copying machine?
Hey!
Oh, my God!
Hey.
Oh...
Look at that, it's
a Christmas miracle!
What are you doing here?
I wanted to be with you.
I missed you so much.
Hey, hey, who'd
you miss the most?
Monica.
Gotcha.
I never want
to leave you again.
But I thought if you
left, you'd get fired.
Turns out they can't fire me...
because I quit.
What?
What? You...
you really quit your job?
Yeah. It's a stupid job and I
could not stand leaving you.
And why should I
be the only one
who doesn't get to do
what he really wants to do?
Well, what do you really want
to do?
I have not thought
this through!
Oh, my God.
I know, I should've talked
to you first about it.
No. I think if this
is what you want to do,
I think it's great.
Thanks.
Chandler, your
being here
is the best Christmas present
I could've ever imagined.
Aw.
Now give me my real gift.
Thank you.
Here, pass these around.
Oh!
Oh, thanks.
"A donation has been made
in your name
to the New York City Ballet."
How did you know?
What?
Are you kidding?
I can't return this.
I thought it was time we started
thinking about other people.
Besides, this gift still says
I love you guys.
Mine says, "To Lillian Meyers."
I don't have a job!
Actuary? No.
Bookkeeper? No.
Topless dancer?
Hey, you know
what I just realized?
You are the sole wage earner.
You are the head
of the household.
I don't do anything.
I'm a kept man!
You are.
Hey, here's 20 bucks.
Why don't you go buy yourself
something pretty
while I'm at
work tomorrow.
Captioned by
Media Access Group at WGBH
access.wgbh.org